<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-19T15:06:00+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sousa Group</title><subtitle>We are a lab based at KCL in London looking to understand the links between oral health and systemic diseases.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Let’s Get Clinical S1 E3: Rizwana Dakri and Mina Pun</title><link href="/2024/08/13/S1E3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let’s Get Clinical S1 E3: Rizwana Dakri and Mina Pun" /><published>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T15:05:18+00:00</updated><id>/2024/08/13/S1E3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/08/13/S1E3.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<iframe style="border-radius:12px" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/0CFokzJ5n20JD8J7jonLI8?utm_source=generator" width="100%" height="352" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy"></iframe>
<!--excerpt end -->

<p>Hello and welcome to Let’s Get Clinical. This week we are a host down but to make up for it we have two guests! We welcome Rizwana Dakri and Mina Pun to discuss their careers thus far and how they have experienced diversity throughout their research journey.</p>

<p>Riz Dakri is a Senior Research Nurse Manager at Guy’s and St Thomas’ NHS Foundation Trust (GSTT), where she has made significant contributions over her impressive 25-year tenure. With a deep commitment to advancing patient care and clinical research, Riz has spent the last 10 years specializing as a research nurse, leading initiatives that bridge the gap between healthcare practice and innovative research. Her extensive experience and leadership in the field have helped to foster a culture of excellence and collaboration, ensuring that patients receive the highest quality of care while participating in ground-breaking studies. Riz is passionate about mentoring the next generation of nurses and continues to advocate for the importance of research in improving health outcomes.</p>

<p>MIna Pun is a Clinical Dental Research Nurse at GSTT, where she has made a great contribution towards research. Mina has a wealth of experience in dental research, with years of experience in a variety of dynamic clinical settings including hospital, community and general dental practice. Mina has worked in a wide variety of dental specialties, including: orthodontics, periodontics, prosthodontics, oral medicine, restorative dentistry, oral and maxillofacial surgery, Implant. Paediatric dentistry, inhalation sedation, IV sedation and general anaesthetic nursing. She is a dedicated clinical research nurse with 2 years of experience in clinical trials.</p>]]></content><author><name>joseph.falconer</name></author><category term="Let&apos;s get clinical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Get Clinical S1 E2: Professor Ronak Rajani</title><link href="/2024/07/29/S1E2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let’s Get Clinical S1 E2: Professor Ronak Rajani" /><published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T15:05:18+00:00</updated><id>/2024/07/29/S1E2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/07/29/S1E2.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<iframe style="border-radius:12px" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/5BIkRUtQbssDSiMaSfa41A?utm_source=generator&amp;t=0" width="100%" height="352" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy"></iframe>
<!--excerpt end -->

<p>Welcome back to Let’s Get Clinical! This week we welcome Professor Ronak Rajani who is a consultant cardiologist in cardiac imaging (echo and CT) and heart valve disease at Guy’s and St Thomas’ NHS Foundation Trust. He is also a Professor of Cardiovascular Imaging at King’s College London and the NIHR CRN lead for cardiovascular Research in South London. In this episode we discuss Prof’s mentors, how to be involved in being a clinician and academic and much more!</p>

<p>Professor Rajani is trained in all forms of multimodality cardiac imaging (cardiac ultrasound, cardiac CT, cardiac MRI and nuclear cardiology) and was the first and only recipient of the BCS/ACC Advanced Cardiac Imaging Fellowship in 2010. This involved 6 months of training at the Royal Brompton Hospital in CMR and Nuclear Cardiology and 6 months at the Cedars Sinai Medical Centre in Los Angeles (CT and PET).</p>

<p>Professor Rajani has an interest in advanced plaque analysis, CT planning for structural intervention and the development of novel applications of cardiac CT with bioengineering and computer processing. He has published in excess of 240 manuscripts in multimodality imaging and has international research collaborations with the US, Europe and Asia.</p>

<p>Professor Rajani is a lead panel member for NICE and sits on the MTAC for novel CT technologies and is on the international sub-committee, best abstract and abstract grading committee of the SCCT. He holds level III accreditation with the SCCT and EAVCI and was awarded Fellow status to the SCCT (FSCCT) for his scientific and service contributions to cardiac CT. In 2023 he was awarded honorary Fellowship to the Royal College of Radiologists (FRCR) for his enduring contribution to education and research in the field of cardiac CT. Professor Rajani is an advisor to industry on CT acquisition protocols for TMVR and has contributed book chapters to the Oxford Handbook of Cardiac CT, the EAVCI handbook on cardiac CT and the ESC Textbook of Cardiovascular Imaging. He is part of the examination writing committee for the EAVCI CT certification exam and is a faculty member of the EAVCI course on Cardiac CT. In 2015 Professor Rajani founded the London CT Academy and thereafter developed the world’s first online CT training course with Professor John Rumberger and the educational company Medmastery. The London CT Academy is now one of the largest of its kind in Europe and has trained more than 350 clinicians from around the world in cardiac CT.</p>

<p>Alongside his considerable experience in cardiac CT, Ronak has 20 years’ experience in cardiac ultrasound (TTE, TEE, Stress echo). He undertook his MD thesis on aortic stenosis from 2002-2005 and he has held British Society of Echocardiography Accreditation for more than ten years. He is an accredited FICE Trainer and Mentor and founded the original FAME Academy with Professor John Chambers in 2013.</p>

<p>Professor Rajani has more than 6510 citations and has an H-index of 41. He is passionate about teaching and education and aims to deliver innovative training courses for a new generation of clinicians with a passion for cardiac imaging like himself.</p>]]></content><author><name>joseph.falconer</name></author><category term="Let&apos;s get clinical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Get Clinical S1 E1: Meet the Hosts!</title><link href="/2024/07/25/S1E1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let’s Get Clinical S1 E1: Meet the Hosts!" /><published>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T15:05:18+00:00</updated><id>/2024/07/25/S1E1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/07/25/S1E1.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<iframe style="border-radius:12px" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/2kop5uJEoKYHsFPbKOXHuC?utm_source=generator" width="100%" height="352" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy"></iframe>
<!--excerpt end -->

<p>The first episode of Let’s Get Clinical is now live on Spotify! Give it a listen!</p>

<p>In this episode we meet our 4 hosts: Mira (a trainee specialist dentist), Joe (a PhD student here at King’s College London) and Bel and Irmak (two undergraduate dentists at King’s). In this episode we discuss what’s to come in this season and what we are looking forward to.</p>]]></content><author><name>joseph.falconer</name></author><category term="Let&apos;s get clinical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ITI Poster presentation of microbial communities in peri-implantitis patients</title><link href="/2024/03/25/ITI-Poster-Post-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ITI Poster presentation of microbial communities in peri-implantitis patients" /><published>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T15:05:18+00:00</updated><id>/2024/03/25/ITI-Poster-Post-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/03/25/ITI-Poster-Post-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>In this video we give a brief explanation of our research. We aimed to investigate microbial communities and resistomes in periodontitis and peri-implantitis patients. We used shotgun metagenomic sequencing to analyse saliva samples and produced taxonomy, ARG and MRG data. Click on this post to watch the video!</p>

<p><img src="https://youtu.be/gFRrHh9v6LE" alt="" /></p>]]></content><author><name>joseph.falconer</name></author><category term="ITI" /><category term="presentation" /><category term="poster" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this video we give a brief explanation of our research. We aimed to investigate microbial communities and resistomes in periodontitis and peri-implantitis patients. We used shotgun metagenomic sequencing to analyse saliva samples and produced taxonomy, ARG and MRG data. Click on this post to watch the video!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ITI Poster presentation of multidisciplinary, person-centred approach for the management of peri-implantitis</title><link href="/2024/03/25/ITI-person-centred-approach.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ITI Poster presentation of multidisciplinary, person-centred approach for the management of peri-implantitis" /><published>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T15:05:18+00:00</updated><id>/2024/03/25/ITI-person-centred-approach</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/03/25/ITI-person-centred-approach.html"><![CDATA[<p>In this video we explain our clinical poster on an integrated, multiidsciplinary, person-centred approach for the management of peri-implantitis. Click on this post to watch the video!</p>

<p><img src="https://youtu.be/xGssecE8gnA" alt="" /></p>]]></content><author><name>joseph.falconer</name></author><category term="ITI" /><category term="presentation" /><category term="poster" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this video we explain our clinical poster on an integrated, multiidsciplinary, person-centred approach for the management of peri-implantitis. Click on this post to watch the video!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Podcast coming soon!</title><link href="/2024/03/19/prior-to-release.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Podcast coming soon!" /><published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T15:05:18+00:00</updated><id>/2024/03/19/prior-to-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/03/19/prior-to-release.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are looking to start releasing episodes for the podcast very soon! Check back again at the end of April for our first episode release! You will be able to listen to us on Spotify, Apple Music and Acast!</p>]]></content><author><name>joseph.falconer</name></author><category term="Let&apos;s" /><category term="get" /><category term="clinical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are looking to start releasing episodes for the podcast very soon! Check back again at the end of April for our first episode release! You will be able to listen to us on Spotify, Apple Music and Acast!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Patient and Public Involvement Panel!!</title><link href="/2023/08/08/focus-group-post-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Patient and Public Involvement Panel!!" /><published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T15:05:18+00:00</updated><id>/2023/08/08/focus-group-post-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/08/08/focus-group-post-3.html"><![CDATA[<p>On the 8th of August 2023, we had our first public involevement panel. The panel took place on teams to allow as many people to join as possible without the hassle of travel. We discussed people’s perception of infective endocarditis and the link to oral health. Also discussed was where and when people had learnt about infective endocarditis. There was a good number of people involved with members of the public, academics and clinical professionals all taking part! If you would like to find out more or would like to get involved next time, just send an email to joseph.falconer@kcl.ac.uk!</p>]]></content><author><name>joseph.falconer</name></author><category term="biology," /><category term="medicine," /><category term="public" /><category term="involvement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the 8th of August 2023, we had our first public involevement panel. The panel took place on teams to allow as many people to join as possible without the hassle of travel. We discussed people’s perception of infective endocarditis and the link to oral health. Also discussed was where and when people had learnt about infective endocarditis. There was a good number of people involved with members of the public, academics and clinical professionals all taking part! If you would like to find out more or would like to get involved next time, just send an email to joseph.falconer@kcl.ac.uk!]]></summary></entry></feed>